# Please review your application

Contact information

Edit

Full Name

Stephen Smith

**Email Address** 

wearypossum4770@yahoo.com

To protect your privacy, we'll mask your email address. The employer will see stephensmith 5644\_m7q@indeedemail.com

City, State

Chattanooga, TN

Phone Number

228-238-2768

Resume

**DownloadEdit** 

# Stephen Smith

#### Graduate Student, Full-Stack Dev.

Chattanooga, TN 37416 stephensmith5644\_m7q@indeedemail.com 228-238-2768

A 10-year US Army Veteran and aspiring software engineer with extensive leadership experience in the realm of patient care, healthcare operations, and agile technology. Pursuing AWS Certified in Academy Cloud Foundations, with a desire to utilize my ever growing skill-set to affect positive change and advance medical communities.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## Work Experience

#### **Health Information Specialists**

Hamilton County Government -Chattanooga, TN September 2020 to October 2020

Managed, verifies, and enters health information data in both paper and electronic formats. Retrieved files and records ensuring timely record filing and retrieval. Assisted with contact tracing and monitoring as assigned. Ensured HIPAA compliance with all data and information. Assisted clients in obtaining COVID-19 test results by conducting phone interviews. Communicated effectively in oral and written form.

#### **Software Engineer-Intern**

Next Health Choice -Chicago, IL May 2020 to July 2020

Contributed 20 additions / alterations to code furthering customer relations. Created and managed new web program to increase operations productivity from by 20%. Researched methods to decrease server response times, and clean code base. Cited Python Enhancement Proposals in commit messages for every code addition. Implemented state-of-the-art techniques from multiple languages improving code readability and maintainability.

#### **Processing Technician II**

Division of Professional Registration - Board of Cosmetology and Barber Examiners - Jefferson City, MO January 2019 to August 2019

Processed applications and fielded incoming calls for an office managing 80,000 professional licenses. Created a Visual Basic for Application Macro to provide faster lookups for areas codes throughout the state. Organized, scanned, verified and archived over 200,000 documents into over 10,000 active and inactive records in a relational database. Managed digitization of official state archives from microfiche which enhanced customer experience, and reduced processing times. Promoted quickly from Processing Technician I to Processing Technician II, a role responsible for issuing professional licenses.

#### **Combat Medic/Healthcare Specialist**

US Armed Forces Army -Fort Leonard Wood, MO February 2009 to January 2019

- Most recent experience Blood Donor Center Technician (Phlebotomy)
- Medical Records
- Electronic Health Record (EHR)
- Patient Assessment
- Intravenous Infusions
- Medication Administration

# Education

#### **Full Stack Development**

Code Platoon -Chicago, IL December 2019 to April 2020

#### **Bachelor's in Emergency Management**

Eastern New Mexico University -Portales, NM 2012 to 2014

# High school or equivalent

Gautier High School -Gautier, MS 2002 to 2006

## **Skills**

•

• Word Processing (10+ years)

•

• Powerpoint (10+ years)

•

• Phlebotomy (7 years)

•

• Medication Administration (7 years)

•

• Medical Terminology (7 years)

•

• Medical Records (5 years)

•

• Customer Service (10+ years)

•

• Auditing (Less than 1 year)

•

• Customer Relationship Management (10+ years)

• Bookkeeping (3 years)

•

• Payroll (1 year)

•

• Microsoft Excel (10+ years)

•

• Accounts Receivable

•

• Process Management

•

• Database Administration

•

• Accounting

•

• Microsoft SQL Server

•

• Databases

•

• Data Warehouse

•

• Agile

•

• Computer Networking

•

• Outlook (10+ years)

•

• SQL

•

• Linux

•

• User Interface (UI)

•

• MySQL

•

• Oracle

•

• Responsive web design

•

• HTML5

•

• Data entry

•

• Title processing

• Typing

#### Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-smith-9559406a/

Military Service

**Branch: United States Army**Service Country: United States
Rank: SGT (Sergeant)

October 2012 to January 2019

#### Certifications and Licenses

#### **Secret Clearance**

#### Assessments

#### Supervisory Skills: Directing Others — Highly Proficient

December 2019

Motivating others to achieve objectives and identifying improvements or corrective actions.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Reliability — Highly Proficient

December 2019

Measures a candidate's tendency to be dependable and come to work.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Written Communication — Proficient

December 2019

Best practices for writing, including grammar, style, clarity, and brevity.

Full results: Proficient

Retail Cashier — Proficient

November 2019

Calculating retail transactions and knowing cash drawer policies and procedures.

Full results: Proficient

Management & Leadership Skills: Planning & Execution — Familiar

December 2019

Planning and managing resources to accomplish organizational goals.

Full results: Familiar

Front Desk Agent (Hotel) — Familiar

December 2019

Selecting hotel rooms based on verbal requests and identifying errors in hotel data

Full results: Familiar

**English Communication Skills: Typing — Expert** 

December 2019

Transcribing text using a standard keyboard

Full results: Expert

Case Management & Social Work — Proficient

January 2020

Prioritizing case tasks, gathering information, and providing services without judgment.

Full results: Proficient

Cooking Skills: Basic Food Preparation — Expert

February 2020

Preparing food, using cooking equipment, and converting ingredient measurements.

Full results: Expert

Food Safety — Highly Proficient

February 2020

Proper food handling, storage, and equipment use for preventing the spread of foodborne illness.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Software Developer Fit — Proficient

July 2020

Measures the traits that are important for successful software developers

Full results: Proficient

**Programming Fundamentals** — **Proficient** 

July 2020

Designed by engineering managers and real-world employers, this test gives you hard data points to evaluate technical

competency

Full results: Proficient

**Customer Focus & Orientation — Proficient** 

April 2020

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity.

Full results: Proficient

Accounting Skills: Bookkeeping — Proficient

August 2020

Calculating and determining the accuracy of financial data

Full results: Proficient

Working with MS Word Documents — Expert

August 2020

Knowledge of various Microsoft Word features, functions, and techniques.

Full results: Expert

Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Highly Proficient

December 2020

Knowledge of various Microsoft Excel features, functions, and formulas

Full results: Highly Proficient

Software Developer Fit — Proficient

July 2020

Measures the traits that are important for successful software developers

Full results: Proficient

#### **Programming Fundamentals** — **Proficient**

July 2020

Designed by engineering managers and real-world employers, this test gives you hard data points to evaluate technical competency

Full results: Proficient

Analyzing Data — Proficient

August 2020

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data

Full results: Proficient

Accounting Skills: Bookkeeping — Proficient

August 2020

Calculating and determining the accuracy of financial data

Full results: Proficient

First aid — Highly Proficient

March 2021

Treating common medical emergencies.

Full results: Highly Proficient

Verbal communication — Proficient

February 2021

Speaking clearly, correctly, and concisely

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

Relevant experience
Edit
Software Engineer- Intern
Next Health Choice
Supporting documents
Edit
Cover letter

LynxDx 333 Jackson Plaza Suite 600 Ann Arbor, MI, 48103 Dear Hiring Manager, Thank you for reviewing my application for the position. I am the best fit for this position because I am passionate as it relates to healthcare and ensuring providers, and patients have necessary information securely, accurately, and rapidly as possible. I continually reevaluated my work and make improvements. Thank you for your time. I look forward to ongoing conversation regarding my potential as a candidate for the position.

| If you | notice | an erro | r in you | r applicati | on, please | contact | <u>Indeed</u> |
|--------|--------|---------|----------|-------------|------------|---------|---------------|
|        |        |         |          |             |            |         |               |

Notify me when similar jobs are available

By creating a job alert, you agree to our <u>Terms</u>. You can change your consent settings at any time by unsubscribing or as detailed in our terms.

By pressing apply: 1) you agree to our <u>Terms, Cookie & Privacy Policies</u>; 2) you consent to your application being transmitted to the Employer (Indeed does not guarantee receipt), & processed & analyzed in accordance with its & Indeed's terms & privacy policies; & 3) you acknowledge that when you apply to jobs outside your country it may involve you sending your personal data to countries with lower levels of data protection.